So now both of my base and my lid had set up to the leather of our stage.
What that means is if I rub it with my finger I am not going to create a indention but if I stick a fingernail in I get a indention really easily.
It is about the consistency of hard cheese.
So I'm going to check my lid fit with my base by flipping it over.
I have not cut it off yet and it is just a little bit too big.
So what I'm going to do is show you how you can fix that problem.
It is a lot better to have a lid that is a little bit too big then a little bit too small because you can trim a lid that is a little bit too big and you can't make a lid that is to small any bigger.
So you put it back on the wheel, now you see it looks wobbly that is because the bat pin hole in my bat are not perfectly symmetrical so I need to spin this around 180 degrees.
And try again.
Now it is on center.
So I would take my ribbon tool, which is call a ribbon tool because it creates a ribbon of clay.
I don't need to take off very much just a little amount and then I would check my lid fit again.
Now it sits nicely on the pot so I would show you the next steps of finishing the lid.